mdanderson.org 2018-02-03

# Website Privacy Policy | MD Anderson Cancer Center

#### Effective Date: Dec. 21, 2017

This Privacy Policy describes how The University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center (“MD Anderson,” “we,” “us,” or “our”)  collects, uses, and shares information about you that we obtain through websites with URLs ending in _mdanderson.org_ ; _[makingcancerhistory.com](http://makingcancerhistory.com/home.html)_ ; _[childrensartproject.org](http://childrensartproject.org/)_ ; and _[childrensart.org](http://childrensartproject.org/)_ (collectively, the “Sites”). This Privacy Policy does not apply to our offline data collection activities, unless otherwise stated below or at the time of collection.  

The practices described in this Privacy Policy are not applied to protected health information. Our privacy practices regarding protected health information are described in our Joint Notice of Privacy Practices. With respect to information you submit through the “request an appointment” form on the Sites, once we have accepted such information, our handling of that information is governed by the Joint Notice of Privacy Practices.

###  Information collection ____

**_Information You Provide To Us_**

We collect information you provide directly to us through the Sites. For example, we collect information when you create an account, subscribe to receive notifications, make a donation or a purchase, apply for a job, or otherwise communicate with us through the Sites.  

The information we collect from you may include personal information. “Personal Information” is information that, whether alone or in combination with other information, can be used to identify an individual (such as first and last name, e-mail address, home address, telephone number, payment card information, or date of birth).  Information that has been de-identified such that it cannot be connected to an individual is not considered Personal Information for purposes of this Privacy Policy.   

_**Information We Collect Automatically**_  

When you access or use the Sites, certain information about your use of the Sites may be collected automatically.  For example, we may collect your IP address, device identifier, browser type, domain name, operating system characteristics, data regarding the device you’re using, and information about your visit, such as access times, duration, and how you arrived at the Sites.  This usage information may be combined with Personal Information, in which case we would treat the combined information as Personal Information.   

In addition to logging information about your visit, we may use various tracking mechanisms such as cookies, web beacons (also known as tracking pixels), and embedded scripts (collectively, “Tracking Technologies”) to automatically collect information about interactions with our Sites or e-mails.  

  * **Cookies** are small text files that a web page server places on your hard drive. The use of cookies is a common practice on many websites. We may place cookies on your computer to allow us to recognize you on the Sites during future visits, to measure web traffic, to offer you certain products or services, or to customize your visit. We use both session ID cookies and tracking cookies. Session cookies make it easier for you to navigate the Sites, and they expire when you close your browser. Tracking cookies help us understand how you use the Sites and enhance your user experience, and they remain on your hard drive for an extended period of time.  
  
Your Internet browser may include settings that permit you to block cookies or to be notified when cookies are placed. Please be aware that if you use these mechanisms to block or remove cookies, certain features and functions of the Sites may be unavailable or may not operate optimally.
  * **Web Beacons** (also called “tracking pixels”) are small graphic images, also known as “Internet tags” or “clear gifs” that are embedded in web pages and e-mail messages. Web beacons may be used for various purposes, such as to count the number of visitors to the Sites, to monitor how users navigate the Sites, or to verify how many articles or links were actually viewed.
  * **Embedded Scripts** are designed to collect information about your interactions with the Sites. These scripts are temporarily downloaded onto your computer from our web server, or the server of a third party with whom we work. They are active only while you are connected to the Sites, and are deleted or deactivated thereafter.

Additional information about Tracking Technologies and your choices concerning their use are explained below in the Analytics Section and under Your Choices. 

**_Information from Other Sources_  
**

We also may obtain information about you from other sources, such as other non-profit organizations, and combine that with information we collect about you. To the extent we combine such third-party sourced information with Personal Information we collect directly from you on the Sites, we will treat the combined information as Personal Information under this Privacy Policy. We are not responsible for the privacy statements or practices of third parties or on any other websites or online services that we do not control.

###  How we may use your information ____

We use information about you to operate the Sites and to deliver the content and services you request. In addition, we may use information about you for other lawful purposes, including to:  

  * Facilitate, manage, personalize and improve your online experience;
  * Respond to your comments, questions and requests, provide customer service, send you informational notices, and contact you if we need to obtain or provide additional information;
  * Manage your online account(s), including purchases, orders, payments, returns, and exchanges;
  * Send you technical notices, updates, security alerts, and support and administrative messages;
  * Communicate with you about products, services, offers, promotions, coupons, newsletters, and events and provide information we think will be of interest to you;
  * Conduct research and analysis, including focus groups and surveys about current services or of potential new services;
  * Prevent and address fraud, breach of policies or terms, and threats or harm; and

Send you advertisements and communicate with you regarding services, products, and events we think may interest you (for information about how to manage e-mail communications, see Your Choices below). 

###  How we may share information ____

We may permit our agents, vendors, consultants, and other service providers to access information collected through the Sites to carry out work on our behalf. This includes a third-party service provider that assists us with processing credit card payments when purchases are made through the Sites. These third party service providers are prohibited from using Personal Information obtained in this manner for any purpose(s) other than to provide the services we have engaged them to perform. We also may share your information:

  * To perform statistical analysis, send you e-mail or postal mail, or provide customer support;
  * With our business partners, affiliates, and other third parties for purposes of sending their own marketing;
  * With our affiliates for internal business purposes;
  * If we are required to do so by law, regulation, or legal process (such as in response to a court order or subpoena);
  * To fulfill requests by government agencies, such as law enforcement authorities;
  * When we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss, or in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual illegal activity; or
  * To enforce our policies, or protect rights, property, or safety.

We also may share your information in connection with, or during negotiations of, any proposed or actual merger, purchase, sale, or any other type of acquisition or business combination of all or any portion of our assets, or any transfer of all or a portion of our business to another company. We reserve the right to transfer any information we obtain through the Sites in the event we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or assets (including in the event of a merger, reorganization, or liquidation).  

###  Information you disclose publicly or to others ____

The Sites may include features, such as message boards, that allow you to freely submit information that can be viewed by others.  We or others may store, display, reproduce, publish, distribute, or otherwise use such information (including the date and time you access the message board) in any media or format, and we may or may not attribute the content to you.  Please keep in mind that if you post information on the Sites using these features, others have the ability to access and share that information with third parties. 

Healthcare-related communications on message boards are not private and can be viewed by the community of cancer discussion participants who also use these features. MD Anderson is not responsible for the privacy, security, accuracy, use, or misuse of any information that you disclose, or that you receive from third parties, via message boards on the Sites.   __

###  Links to other websites ____

The Sites may include hyperlinks to other websites, online locations, platforms, or services for your convenience and information. Such linked websites may be operated by third parties that are not owned or controlled by MD Anderson. They may use their own cookies, web beacons, and other Tracking Technologies to collect information about you, and they may solicit Personal Information directly from you. If you follow links from the Sites to other websites, we encourage you to familiarize yourself with their privacy policies and terms of use. We are not responsible for the content or privacy practices of websites that we do not control.

###  Analytics services, advertising and online tracking ____

We may engage and work with third parties to serve advertisements on our behalf on the Sites or on other websites, and to provide analytics services about use of the Sites and performance of our ads and content on other websites. In addition, we may participate in online advertising networks and exchanges that display relevant advertisements to visitors, both on the Sites and on other websites, based on the visitors’ interests as reflected by their browsing habits. Third parties may use cookies and other Tracking Technologies to automatically collect information about you and your activities, such as registering a unique identifier for your device and tying that to your online activities on and off of our Sites. We may use this information to analyze and track data, determine the popularity of certain content, deliver advertising and content targeted to your interests, and better understand your online activity. 

Information about your use of the Sites and other websites may be collected using Tracking Technologies across time and services, and used for various purposes such as to associate different devices you use, and to deliver relevant and retargeted content, including interest-based ads.   

Your web browser may have settings that allow you to transmit a “Do Not Track” signal when you visit various websites or use online services. Like many websites, the Sites are not designed to respond to “Do Not Track” signals received from browsers. To learn more about “Do Not Track” signals, [click here](https://allaboutdnt.com/).  

###  Your choices ____

_**Accessing and Changing Information.**_

With few exceptions, you are entitled on your request to be informed about the information MD Anderson collects about you. Under Sections 552.021 and 552.023 of the Texas Government Code, you are entitled to receive and review the information. Under Section 559.004 of the Texas Government Code, you are entitled to have MD Anderson Cancer Center correct information about you that is held by us and that is incorrect, in accordance with the procedures set forth in The University of Texas System Business Procedures Memorandum 32. 

The information that MD Anderson Cancer Center collects will be retained and maintained as required by Texas records retention laws (Section 441.180 et seq. of the Texas Government Code) and rules. Different types of information are kept for different periods of time.

**_Communications_  
**

You can opt out of receiving promotional e-mails from us by clicking on the unsubscribe link in the email, or by changing your communication preferences when you log on to your account.  Please note that your opt-out will not affect subsequent subscriptions or non-promotional communications from us, such as such as administrative and service announcements.  

**_Tracking Technologies Generally_  
**

Regular cookies generally may be disabled or removed using tools available as part of most commercial browsers. In some instances, a browser may include settings that allow you to preemptively block cookies from being placed on your computer. Please be aware that if you disable or remove cookies and similar technologies, some parts of the Sites may not work properly. Also, if you revisit the Sites from a different computer or using a different browser, you may not be able to limit browser-based Tracking Technologies in the same way.   

**_Analytics Services and Interest-Based Ads_  
**

The Sites use third-party web analytics services, such as Adobe Analytics and Google Analytics, to help us analyze how visitors use the Sites. For further information about Adobe Analytics and how they use analytics data, [click here](http://www.adobe.com/privacy/analytics.html). To go directly to an opt-out tool for Adobe Analytics, [click here](http://www.adobe.com/privacy/opt-out.html#4). To learn more about opting out of data collection through Google Analytics, [click here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).   

Certain advertising networks and exchanges participate in the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”). NAI has developed a tool that allows consumers to opt out of certain interest-based advertising delivered by NAI members’ ad networks. To learn more about opting out of such targeted advertising or to use the NAI tool, [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/). Please be aware that such opt-outs do not affect non-targeted ads. We are not responsible for the effectiveness of, or compliance with, any third-parties’ opt-out mechanisms or programs, or the accuracy of their statements regarding their programs.    

###  Your California privacy rights ____

California’s “Shine the Light” law permits customers in California to request certain details about how certain types of their information are shared with third parties and, in some cases, affiliates, for those third parties’ and affiliates’ own direct marketing purposes. Under this law, a business must either provide California customers certain information upon request, or permit California customers to opt-in to, or opt-out of, this type of sharing.

We may elect to share certain information about you that we have collected through the Sites with third parties for those third parties’ direct marketing purposes. If you are a California resident, you may request information about our compliance with this law by contacting us at [PrivacyCompliance@mdanderson.org](mailto:PrivacyCompliance@mdanderson.org)  or by sending a letter to the Chief Privacy Officer at The University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center, Institutional Compliance Office, Unit 1640, P.O. Box 301407, Houston, TX, 77230-1407. Requests must include “California Privacy Rights Request” in the first line of the description and include your name, street address, city, state, and ZIP code. Please note that we are only required to respond to one request per customer each year, and we are not required to respond to requests made by means other than through the e-mail address or postal mail address listed here.  

###  Children's privacy ____

The Sites are not targeted to children under the age of thirteen (13), however, we from time-to-time we may have special sections intended, in whole or in part, for children. As a State of Texas government agency that conducts not-for-profit educational programs, we need not comply with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (“COPPA”) requirements. For more information regarding our privacy practices for these sections of the Sites, see any applicable program-specific supplemental privacy notice that is posted on those Site pages.

Any California residents under the age of eighteen (18) who have registered to use the Sites, and who have posted content or information on the Sites, can request that such information be removed from the Sites by contacting us at [PrivacyCompliance@mdanderson.org](mailto:PrivacyCompliance@mdanderson.org) or by sending a letter to the Chief Privacy Officer at The University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center, Institutional Compliance Office, Unit 1640, P.O. Box 301407, Houston, TX, 77230-1407, stating that they personally posted such content or information and detailing where the content or information is posted. We will make reasonable good faith efforts to remove the post from prospective public view or anonymize it so the minor cannot be individually identified. This removal process cannot ensure complete or comprehensive removal. For instance, third-parties may have republished the post and archived copies of it may be stored by search engines and others that we do not control.

###  Data security ____

We take reasonable measures to help protect personal information collected through the Sites from loss, theft, misuse, and other unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction.  Nevertheless, transmission via the Internet is not completely secure and we cannot guarantee the security of your information collected through our Sites.

###  Information for users outside the United States ____

MD Anderson is based in the U.S. and the information we collect is governed by U.S. law.  If you are accessing the Sites from outside the U.S., please be aware that information collected through the Sites may be transferred to, processed, and stored in the U.S. Data protection laws in the U.S. may be different from those of your country of residence. Your use of the Sites, and providing information through the Sites, constitutes your consent to the transfer, processing, usage, sharing, and storage of your information, including Personal Information, in the U.S. as set forth in this Privacy Policy.   

###  Changes to this Privacy Policy ____

We reserve the right to revise and reissue this Privacy Policy at any time. Any changes will be effective immediately upon posting of the revised Privacy Policy, and the new effective date will be listed at the top of this page. Subject to applicable law, your continued use of the Sites indicates your consent to the terms of the posted Privacy Policy. We encourage you to periodically review this Privacy Policy.

###  Contact us ____

If you have requests relating to your Personal Information, or if you have questions about this Privacy Policy, you may submit your questions online at <https://www4.mdanderson.org/contact/ask-a-question/index.cfm>, or contact us by emailing [PrivacyCompliance@mdanderson.org](mailto:PrivacyCompliance@mdanderson.org), sending a letter to the Chief Privacy Officer at The University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center, Institutional Compliance Office, Unit 1640, P.O. Box 301407, Houston, TX, 77230-1407, or calling 1-877-632-6789.
